Allen, Barry mss., 1941-1993 LMC 2784
Lilly Library
Allen, Barry mss.
1941-1993
Lilly Library
Allen, Barry, 1943-
LMC 2784
2 Boxes 2 standard
The Allen, Barry mss. consists of various scripts and screenplays collected by Barry Allen, 1943-.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchase: 2009, Gift: 2012
Biographical Note
Barry Allen was born in Indianapolis, Indiana, in December 1943. Despite initial aspirations of being a newspaper photojournalist, Kevin Brownlow's The Parade's Gone By and working with a large library of classic films at Channel 8 shifted Allen's career interests to the programming and ultimately the preservation of moving images. In 1967, he started working as an editor for WISH-TV in Indianapolis, where he edited on 16mm all movies that would be broadcast. In subsequent years, he transitioned to booking and programming repertory and commercial films for Heaston Theatres in Indianapolis. In 1999, he was assigned the role of film preservationist for the Republic Pictures library, a subsidiary holding of Paramount & Viacom. In the mid 2000s, he became the Executive Director of Film Preservation and Archival Resources at Paramount Pictures. In 2005, Allen was awarded the Anthology Film Archives Honor for his work to preserve the Republic Pictures library. Allen retired from Paramount Pictures in 2010.
Scope and Contents
The Allen, Barry mss. consists of various scripts and screenplays, including Sunset Boulevard (1950), The Browning Version (1951), The Searchers (1956), Parrish (1961), Leo the Last (1970), The Day of the Locust (1975), and Cradle Will Rock (1999), collected by Barry Allen, 1943-.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged following descending dates
Indiana University -- Alumni and alumnae; Motion pictures; Allen, Barry, 1943-
- Screenplay Scripts, 1941-1993 (Box 1)
  - The Maltese Falcon, May 26, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Sunset Boulevard, Dec. 21, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Sunset Boulevard, Release Script, Jan. 24, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - The Greatest Show on Earth, Release Script, Jan. 7, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - The Searchers, Revised Final Screenplay, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Parrish, Feb. 11, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Midnight Cowboy, Combined Continuity, May, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - On Her Majesty's Secret Service, Release Script, Dec., 1969 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Adventures of Gerard, Release Script, Jan., 1970 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Leo the Last, Release Script, Feb., 1970 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - The Private Life of Sherlock Holmes, Combined Continuity, Sep., 1970 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Von Richthofen and Brown, April 9, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Sunday-Bloody Sunday, Release Script, May 16, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Pulp, Release Script, July, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - The Day of the Locust, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - The Cradle Will Rock, Nov. 9, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - The Browning Version, Screenplay, May 28, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 17)